DANA J. GANT

4840 W. Leodra Lane, Laveen, AZ 85339 danagant11@gmail.com (480) 209-9380

Professional Profile

Experienced Certified Lactation Consultant and Mother/Baby/Postpartum professional with demonstrable staff and supervisory skills developed from over twenty years in acute hospital settings and eight years as a multi-state licensed travel nurse. A resourceful as well as creative manager of individual breastfeeding challenges in both outpatient and in-patient settings. Passionate about team-building and mentoring in order to tailor effective lactation education to the individual needs of mothers.

Specialties

Mother/Baby-Postpartum Lactation Consultant Medical/Surgical Unit

Relevant Work Experience

Washington Hospital Fremont, CA 9/2017 – Present

Per Diem position

Facility Type: Acute Care Unit: Mother/ Baby
Trauma Level: 2

Unit beds: 28

Total Beds: 385

Patient ratio: 1-15

- Provide research-based lactation support and education to breastfeeding mothers.
- Coordinate with pediatricians to resolve complex breastfeeding issues in outpatient clinic
- € Educate and train 150 staff nurses in preparation for Baby Friendly Designation
- Daily hospital rounds made to breastfeeding mothers in need of assistance for latching infant

EREER!

Community Bridges/Rehab Centers Phoenix, AZ 1/2019- Present

Health Temp PRN

Medical, Psych and Drug Unit

- Provide care for patients in secure unit with medical and addiction issues
- Triage complex medical diagnoses for transfer to higher level of care
- Assess medical stability to determine need for drug detoxification

Kaiser Redwood City Redwood City, CA 7/2017 – 10/2017 AMN – Travel Staff Nurse

Facility Type: Acute Care Unit: Mother-Baby Trauma Level: 2 Unit beds: 32

Total Beds: 149 Patient ratio: 1-4

Assessment of pain symptoms for cesarean birth mothers

Provide care of cesarean and vaginal delivery dyad

Central Washington Hospital Wenatchee, WA 4/2017 – 6/2017 AMN – Travel Staff Nurse

Facility Type: Acute Care Unit: Medical/Surgical

Trauma Level: 3 Unit Beds: 27

Total Beds: 198

Assessment and care of medical & surgical patients

Medication administration along with initiation, administration and monitoring of IV therapy

Mountain Vista Medical Center

Mesa, AZ

1/2017 - 7/2017

Health Temp PRN Mother - Baby

Facility Type: Acute Care Unit: Mother-Baby Trauma Level: 2 Unit beds: 11 Patient ratio: 1-4

Provide care for postpartum mothers and infants

Assist with breastfeeding and education

Discharge planning and transitioning to home

Scottsdale Liberty Hospital

Scottsdale, AZ

10/2016 - 12/2016

Health Temp PRN

Medical - Surgical

Temp Nurse

- Direct care of and assessment of adult surgical patients
- Provide routine treatment and post-surgical care
- Educate patient and families on disease processes, medical-surgical procedures including medication and pain management techniques

United Hospital
St. Paul, MN
9/2016 – 10/2016
Medical Solutions
Strike Nurse/Lactation Consultant
Mother-Baby

- Direct care of mother and baby after delivery
- Counsel mothers on newborn nursery nursing care
- Promote and assesses maternal infant bonding
- Breastfeeding education and assistance provided

Community Regional Medical Center Fresno, CA 1/2016 – 4/2016 Axion Healthcare Travel Nurse

Mother-Baby Unit

- Educate and instruct new parents on caring for newborn infant
- Monitor mothers to ensure healthy recovery is progressing physically and emotionally
- Ensure mother is comfortable bonding and feeding infant

Hemet Valley Medical Center Hemet, CA 8/2015 – 12/15 Aya Healthcare Travel Nurse Mother-Baby Unit

- Assess, evaluate and educate mothers on caring for self after vaginal or cesarean birth
- Evaluate and administrate medication for pain as needed

Sharp Mary Birch Hospital – San Diego, CA 12/2014 – 2/2015 MAS Staffing

Travel Nurse-Lactation Consultant Mother-Baby Unit

- Provide education and assistance to mothers with breastfeeding concerns and questions
- Assist with staff development to increase confidence with breastfeeding skills

Phoenix Baptist Hospital
Phoenix, AZ
12/2012 – 12/2013
Supplemental Healthcare
Temp assignment/Float Nurse
Mother/Baby Unit
Medical-surgical

University of Minnesota-Fairview Minnesota, MN 8/2012 – 11/2012 Aureus Medical

Travel Nurse/Lactation Consultant Mother-Baby Unit

- Nursing care for postpartum mothers and infants after delivery in teaching facility
- Educate families on newborn care
- Assisted with teaching medical students during their rotation

Education and Credentials

Bachelor of Science in Education Associate Degree in Nursing University of Wisconsin-Whitewater East Los Angeles College

Registered Nurse licensure: (Current) Arizona, California, Massachusetts, Minnesota, New York, and Oregon (Expired) Alaska, Connecticut, District of Columbia, Georgia, Pennsylvania, and Washington.

IBCLC: International Board Certified Lactation Consultant (#L-11222) Issuer: International Board of Lactation Consultant Examiners

Certification: 11/1998 - 12/2023

ACLS – Advanced Cardiac Life Support BLS - Basic Life Support Issuer: American Heart Association Issuer: American Heart Association

Expiration 8/2020 Expiration: 6/ 2020

NRP – Neonatal Resuscitation Program Issuer: American Heart Association

Expiration: 9/2020

Computer Skills

- **EPIC**
- McKesson
- **Cerner**
- Meditech